<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on DataSorcery</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on DataSorcery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Income Data and plotting themes</title>
      <link>/posts/tt-income-data-and-plotting-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tt-income-data-and-plotting-themes/</guid>
      <description>A while since I&amp;rsquo;ve completed a tidy tuesday challenge here so to get back in the swing of things I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a fairly simple plot of income equality by race and focused on altering the default these to try to create a more striking visual effect for the data.
Code The code is pretty straight forward to create the chart. The key effect I was going for here was to alter the theme to make a more striking visual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday NFL data</title>
      <link>/posts/tidy-tuesday-nfl-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tidy-tuesday-nfl-data/</guid>
      <description>Did the best team win the Superbowl?
Armed with the Tidy Tuesday data from NFL seasons back to 2000 I set out to answer the question above. With a rudimentary metric assessing the team strength based on margin of victory and strength of schedule. I created a quick data viz showing that less than third of the time the team ranked top by this metric has won the superbowl
The viz Using the ggimage package to bring a bit of Lombardi glitz to the data viz and a little bit of data wrangling to rank and join the superbowl winners with the top ranked team data gave us this output</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Spotify data</title>
      <link>/posts/tt-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tt-spotify/</guid>
      <description>This weeks Tidy Tuesday challenge centred around Spotify data, over 32,000 songs from multiple genres from the 60s to today. Given this was my first Tidy Tuesday for a while I decided to go for something relatively quick and simple to try to get back into the habit and look at the popularity of different types of music over time.
Code Having read in the data the next step was to make a quick modification to allow me to work with dates as opposed to character values.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
